知道他的全名吗?
Would you know his full name?
我不熟这孩子.
l barely knew the kid.
吉.
Jim.
- 好像叫吉.
- 詹姆斯.
- Jim.
- James.
叫詹姆斯·赫尔利.
James Hurley.
他说他是从双峰镇来的.
He said he was from Twin Peaks.
他是个流窜者.
He's a drifter.
当玛舒太太把车停在路边时
估计他已经流窜已久了.
He was probably long gone by the time
Mr. Marsh pulled out of the driveway.
他在这儿干了很长时间?
Did he work here long?
玛舒太太雇他
在这儿修积架.
Mrs. Marsh hired him
to fix the Jaguar.
积架...
Jaguar...
积--架-- 一辆跑车.
J-A-G-W-- A car.
你是怎么碰见他的, 玛舒太太?
How did you meet him, Mrs. Marsh?
杰弗里的积架在沃里吧
附近抛锚了.
Jeffrey's Jaguar broke down
near Wallies.
我跑进去借电话打.
l went in to use the phone.
他说能帮忙.
He offered to help.
好, 我们会去查的. 谢谢你.
Okay, we'll check that. Thank you.
那么我们向
詹姆斯·赫尔利告别吧.
And so we bid adieu
to James Hurley.
别说了.
Give it a rest.
小心点, 伊夫林.
Careful, Evelyn.
我可不肯定我能容忍
一个神经兮兮的同谋.
l'm not sure l can tolerate
a nervous co-conspirator.
我只想它快点结束, 好了吧?
l just want it over with, all right?
都依你了, 玛舒太太.
Anything you say, Mrs. Marsh.
詹姆斯, 我们靠自己是
摆不平这事的.
James, we can't get out of this
by ourselves.
我们得找人
帮我们.
We're gonna need someone
to help us.
我什么都没干.
l didn't do anything.
是马科杀了玛舒先生.
我是被人陷害的.
Malcolm killed Mr. Marsh.
l'm being framed.
要我给你拿点什么喝吗,
海沃德小姐?
Can l get you something,
Miss Hayward?
不. 不, 谢谢你.
No. No, thank you.
看, 这没什么区别.
Look, it doesn't make any difference.
我们不能干坐着
等警察来捉我们.
We can't wait for the cops
to catch us.
- 我觉得我应该给艾德打电话.
- 别, 别, 不要.
- l think l should call Ed.
- No, no, don't.
我得-- 我唯一的机会
就是亲自去和伊夫林谈谈.
l gotta-- My only chance
is to talk to Evelyn myself.
如果她能告诉我这是个陷阱,
或许她也会这样和警察说的.
lf she told me that this was all a setup,
maybe she'll just tell the police that too.
真的不来点儿吗?
You're sure?
真的.
Yeah.
你一个机会都没有.
警察早就在那等着你了.
You wouldn't have a chance.
The cops will be waiting for you.
我们得继续赶路.
We've gotta keep moving.
可是她会听我的.
我知道她会的.
She'd listen to me though.
l know she would.
她会吗?
Would she?
为什么?
Why?
我必须给电话艾德.
l'm gonna go call Ed.
留在这.
Stay here.
嗨, 艾德? 嗨, 是唐娜.
Hi, Ed? Hi, it's Donna.
听着, 我来不及多说了,
但詹姆斯惹麻烦了.
Listen, l don't have a lot of time,
but l think James is in trouble.
嗯, 他一直在给
一个女人打工.
Well, he's been working
for this woman.
帮她修车,
Working on her car,
然后
出了个交通事故，之后...
and l think
there's been this accident and...
嗨, 好吗, 伊薇?
Hi, how are you doing, Yvette?
听着, 我听说你
你有新男友了.
Listen, l heard about
your new boyfriend.
是啊, 那太好了, 真的.
Yeah, that's great, really.
听到这消息真好.
Good to hear it.
那么和我讲讲他的事.
So tell me about him.
- 打搅了.
- 海, 法兰.
- Excuse me.
- Hi, Frank.
昨晚你在雪莉家
干什么, 波比?
What were you doing
at Shelly's house last night, Bobby?
雪莉差点就被杀死了
你还有心思问我在那干什么?
Shelly almost gets murdered and
you're worried about what l'm doing?
怎么不问问里欧那饭桶?
What about Leostein?
你到底在
雪莉家干嘛?
What were you doing
at Shelly's house?
看, 就说白了吧.
Look, here's the deal.
雪莉和我好上了, 行了吧?
Shelly and l are together, okay?
劳拉死前,
我们就在一起好一阵子了,
We have been for a long time,
since before Laura died,
还有在里欧痴呆流口水的
之前之后都在一起.
before and after Leo
went into his drool mode.
波比?
Bobby?
锯木厂失火那晚
你在哪儿?
Where were you
the night the mill burned?
那和这有什么关系?
What's that got to do with this?
里欧要杀死你.
Leo tried to kill you.
- 你就开枪打他.
- 不可能.
- Maybe you shot him.
- No way.
木厂失火那晚
我去找雪莉了,
l went to Shelly's
the night the mill burned down,
因为我担心她.
because l was worried about her.
汉克·詹宁斯的子弹
穿过窗户打中他时
He was about to bury an ax
in my head
他差点就把斧头
砍进我脑袋了.
when Hank Jennings shot him
through the window.
- 你肯定是汉克吗?
- 绝对是.
- You sure it was Hank?
- Absolutely.
里欧和汉克之间有什么关系?
What's Hank's connection with Leo?
我不知道, 爷儿.
不如你来告诉我好了?
l don't know, man.
Why don't you tell me?
雪莉, 你觉得里欧
现在会在哪儿?
Shelly, do you have any idea
where Leo might be now?
不, 我不知道.
No, l don't.
我会派2个警官去你家
一天24小时.
l'll assign a couple of my deputies
to the house 24 hours a day.
嘿, 爷儿,
我能照顾雪莉，好吗.
Hey, man,
l can take care of Shelly all right.
你就省了派警官吧.
You can just save the deputies.
波比·布里格斯,
Bobby Briggs,
打住.
button it.
- 你现在可以走了.
- 行.
- You can go now.
- Okay.
雪莉, 别担心, 我们不会
让你离开视线范围的.
Shelly, don't worry, we're not
gonna let you out of our sight.
- 谢谢你.
- 来吧, 雪莉.
- Thank you.
- Come on, Shelly.
我觉得安全多了,
是吧, 雪莉?
l feel so much safer,
don't you, Shelly?
波比.
Bobby.
悠着点, 小流氓.
Get a life, punk.
先生们.
Gentlemen.
又一趟「西雅图到
双峰镇" 的穿梭之旅.
Another trip on the ''Seattle
to Twin Peaks'' shuttle.
你好吗?
How are you?
- 看来挺好嘛, 哈里.
- 是啊.
- Looking good, Harry.
- Yeah.
- 艾伯特.
- 库.
- Albert.
- Coop.
- 先生们.
- 你带什么来了?
- Gentlemen.
- What have you got?
我回来双峰镇就是为了.
My invite back to Twin Peaks.
云顿·厄尔.
戈登·寇尔直接命令的.
Windom Earle.
Direct orders from Gordon Cole.
正如他自己说的:
As he so succinctly put it:
"我担心库呢."
''l'm worried about Coop.''
斯普林菲尔德, 堪萨斯城,
罗敦市, 达拉斯, 杰克逊.
Springfield, Kansas City,
Lawton, Dallas, Jackson.
厄尔都已经
给警察局和
Earle's been sending
gift-wrapped packages
主要执法机关
送过礼包了.
to police departments
and major law enforcement agencies.
每个看起来都像是邮包炸弹,
但最后都被证实无害.
Each looks like a mail bomb,
but they turn out to be harmless.
快递员收到
云顿·厄尔签名的假信用卡.
The deliveries were paid for by a phony
credit card signed Windom Earle.
盒子里是什么?
What's in the boxes?
每个都装着一件服饰.
One article of clothing in each.
1, 一条白面纱, 2, 一条吊袜带,
3, 一双白便鞋,
One, a white veil, two, a garter,
three, a pair of white slippers,
4 , 一条珍珠项链,
最后, 一套婚纱.
four, a pearl necklace,
and finally, a wedding dress.
是凯若琳的.
Caroline's.
毒监部和联邦调查局要捉他,
更别说密西西比州, 俄克拉何马州
He's got DEA and FBl,
not to mention Mississippi, Oklahoma
和伊利诺斯州的巡逻队了
都在通缉他.
and lllinois State patrols
looking for him.
大家都被邀请到舞会里了.
Everyone's invited to the party.
但我猜, 除了你，库
他不会和任何人共舞.
But my guess is, he won't dance
with anyone but you, Coop.
办公室的流浪汉
死因是大动脉被切断.
The vagrant from the office died
from a knife wound severing the aorta.
这家伙的手指
直指着这颗棋子.
This guy's finger is pointed
directly at this chess piece.
但是尸体已经僵直了
厄尔是怎样做到这一点呢?
How did Earle manage that
with the rigor mortis?
嗯, 新死的人是从头开始
慢慢僵硬之脚趾.
Well, rigor mortis goes
from head to toe.
但2天之后,
僵直会从脚趾向头部逆行一次.
But after two days,
it leaves the body from toe to head.
那么他就等逆行，
至手臂手指处
So he waited for it to leave
the arms and the fingers
再将它们指向
棋盘上.
so they could be maneuvered
onto the chess board.
然后又装神弄鬼
把发电站炸个底朝天.
And then he played Zeus
at the power station.
- 发现什么了?
- 就这地图.
- What was found?
- This map.
粘在桌子底下.
Taped to the bottom of a table.
干的好, 艾伯特.
Good work, Albert.
毫无疑问.
他已经开始行动了.
He's making his move.
Most definitely.
是啊.
Yeah.
哦, 库, 你这身打扮.
Oh, Coop, about the uniform.
怎么了, 艾伯特?
Yes, Albert?
比起你那套优雅的
黑西服加领带
Replacing the quiet elegance
of the dark suit and tie
这身土里巴叽的
泥色便服
with the casual indifference
of these muted earth tones
简直就是自毁潮流,
不过我也疯了吧.
is a form of fashion suicide,
but call me crazy.
看起来穿在你身上, 还行.
On you, it works.
谢谢你, 艾伯特.
Thank you, Albert.
啊哈，你醒了.
You're awake then.
想必你睡的很香吧?
l trust you've slept well?
你睡着的时候,
我已经全部了解你过了.
While you've slept,
l've learned all about you.
里欧·强生.
Leo Johnson.
警察可想尽快
见到你呢.
The police would like to see you
as soon as possible.
现在, 让我来看看.
Now, let me see.
走私毒品.
Drug trafficking.
纵火.
Arson.
谋杀未遂.
Attempted murder.
家庭暴力.
我喜欢这部分.
Domestic violence.
Now l am partial to that.
好了, 里欧, 我已经清洗过你的伤口.
Well, Leo, l've cleansed your wounds.
你会好的.
You're on the mend.
我已经除去了
你的肉中刺.
l've removed the proverbial thorn
from your paw.
里欧. 里欧是狮子王.
Leo. Leo the lion.
现在...
Now...
我想你帮助我.
l want you to help me.
和服从我.
And obey me.
你会照办吗?
Will you do that?
你知道吗,
在13世纪的日本,
Did you know that,
in the 1 3th century in Japan,
武士被剥夺了
他们的武器之后.
the samurai were stripped
of their weaponry.
他们却发现常年
佩戴在身的
But they discovered that the aged
and treated bamboo
尺八长笛
可以当作出色的短棒来使用.
of their shakuhachi flute
made an excellent cudgel.
这长笛
真实个令人愉快的好乐器啊.
This flute
is truly an instrument of pleasure.
你不觉得吗?
Don't you think?
这项链我本想留着
合适场合才用,
l wanted to save this necklace
for an occasion,
但你破坏气氛了.
but you've ruined it.
现在...
Now...
过来这儿.
Come over here.
我给你煮了些稀粥.
l've made you some gruel.
过来, 里欧, 来吃你的稀粥.
Come on, Leo, eat your gruel.
好滋味, 香喷喷.
Yum, yum.
一转眼20年了, 宝贝儿.
lt's been 20 years, babe.
毕业舞会
似乎还是昨日之事
One day we're talking
about a graduation party
而如今我们却已在这了.
and the next day we're here.
除了无尽感伤
就什么都没有了.
And in between
nothing but a world of hurt.
我尽量不去想它.
l tried not to think about it.
我把时间越来越多
放在餐馆的生意上,
l just spent
more and more time at the diner,
努力让它好好运作起来.
trying to make the place work.
因为除此之外，我就一无所有了.
Because l had nothing else.
我们每天如常开门,
We were open every day,
这样我就不会想去过
另一种生活了.
so l wouldn't have to have
another life.
不过生日,
No birthdays,
不过国庆,
no Fourth of July,
也不过圣诞.
no Christmas.
嗯, 我把我所有的圣诞节
都变成工作日.
Well, l turned all my Christmases
into a week full of Mondays.
当这样也不起作用时,
When that didn't work,
我就开始想那些礼物
那些我从没给你买过.
l thought about all the presents
l never bought you.
也从来没送过你的礼物.
Never got to give you.
我去年给你
买了圣诞礼物.
l bought you a present
last Christmas.
是一条绿宝石镶嵌玛瑙的饰扣宝路领带.
lt was a turquoise and onyx bolo tie.
我走到你家门前
想把它送给你,
l walked over to your house
to give it to you,
但我没敢进去.
but l couldn't go in.
我只是默默等着.
l just waited.
看着你在窗前走过.
l could see you through the window.
我不知道我为什么没敢进去.
l don't know why l couldn't go in.
对不起，我没做到.
l'm sorry l didn't.
我常想,
All that time,
在我家里的，在我床上的.
you should have been in my home.
本应该是你.
ln my bed.
重要的是将来, 艾德.
lt's about the future now, Ed.
和我们的将来要做点什么.
And what we're gonna do about it.
今晚，我餐厅关门后
我想你来接我.
l want you to come tonight
after l close the diner.
接我回家.
Take me home.
你是对的.
You're right.
未来就在我们前方.
lt's all ahead of us.
有的是时间.
Plenty of time.
小艾艾?
Eddie?
- 小艾艾?
- 不, 不, 不.
- Eddie?
- No, no, no.
我还是现在和她谈谈好.
l may as well talk to her now.
你好, 纳丁.
Hello, Nadine.
我在刀河
一路杀进区决赛,
l got all the way
to the district finals at Knife River,
却只为了
空中灌篮是违规的.
only to find out
the airplane slam is illegal.
我就这样被取消资格了.
l was disqualified.
第二名, 真讨厌.
Second place, what a drag.
噢, 好小子, 有够倒霉的, 哼?
Oh, boy, what a tough break, huh?
你好, 纳丁.
Hello, Nadine.
l owe you an apology, Norma.
我得向你道歉, 诺玛.
我是说, 我真是把汉克揍惨了这次
很对不起.
l mean, l really pounded Hank
and l am sorry.
因为当时我以为
他真会伤到小艾艾.
But l thought he was gonna do
something to Eddie.
所以我就抓狂了.
And l sort of got mad.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
知道么?
Know what?
l know about you guys.
你们的事我都知道了.
真的, 真的没问题.
lt's really, really okay.
因为这样我就不会为
我和迈克的事感到太内疚了.
Because l don't have to feel so guilty
about me and Mike.
你和迈克?
You and Mike?
我不想陷进去的,
但我不得不告诉你,
l don't wanna get into it,
but l have to tell you,
这是非常, 非常认真的.
it is really, really serious.
So you guys can go ahead
and do whatever you want.
那么你们该干什么
就干什么去吧.
我对此已经
完全没感觉了.
l am completely cool
about all of this.
真的.
Really.
乔西...
Josie...
是这样的.
This is it.
西雅图警方想要答案
我得告诉他们点什么.
The Seattle police want answers
and l have to tell them something.
他们知道你和乔纳森
有关系.
They know you were connected
with Jonathan.
他怎么死的?
How did he die?
他后脑
中了3枪.
He was shot three times
in the back of the head.
乔西...
Josie...
如果你以前从未说过真相,
lf you were ever gonna tell the truth,
现在就是个最佳时机了.
now would be an ideal time.
我想得再来一杯咖啡了.
Think l'll get another cup of joe.
是你吗, 皮特?
ls that you, Pete?
- 是我. 库珀?
- 在.
- Yeah. Cooper?
- Yeah.
终于从一大堆杂活里脱开身了
l get over to the Clean and Save
吉尼·帕勃列
还在柜台那边忙着呢.
and Jeanie Pombelek
is working the counter.
She does not speak
one word of English.
她连一句英语
都不会说.
一个词都不会, 上了拉链似的.
Nada, zip.
她是从布达佩斯来的.
She's from Budapest.
我们就站在那儿
你眼看我眼的
We just stood there
and looked at each other
像木头人一样.
like we were made of wood.
这些衣服是谁的, 皮特?
Who does all this belong to, Pete?
凯萨琳把她使唤来
使唤去，快把她累死了.
Catherine's been running her
into the ground.
- 要帮忙?
- 所以我就贡献点力量
- Need a hand?
- So l offered to stop
by the dry cleaners
and pick up Josie's stuff.
中途停个便车
去帮乔西拿点东西.
知道么, 匈牙利语
我只会2个词，红辣椒和菜炖牛肉.
You know, the only words l know
in Hungarian are paprika and goulash.
lt took me 20 minutes
to get this stuff.
我先去放好这些东西
就20分钟.
我来接. 来帮个手.
Let me get that. Give me a hand.
Hello.
你好.
稍等.
Just hold a minute.
- 找乔西的. 她在吗?
- 她在另一间房, 皮特.
- lt's for Josie. ls she here?
- She's in the other room, Pete.
- Hello.
- Josie.
- 你好.
- 乔西.
我是托马斯.
lt's Thomas.
我真高兴终于找到你了.
l'm so glad l've found you.
我之前一直在想
我们还能再续前缘吗.
l was wondering
if we could get together.
你知道
乔纳森发生什么了吗?
Did you hear about
what happened to Jonathan?
可怕吧.
Dreadful.
欢迎到双峰镇,
埃卡先生.
Welcome to Twin Peaks,
Mr. Eckhardt.
她又回到凯萨琳·马爹利身边了.
She's run back to Catherine Martell.
l'm so disappointed.
我很失望.
So l asked Stonewall Jackson
what he would like to do
于是，我就问史东沃·杰克逊
在我们把那些北佬
赶到加拿大去之后
他最想干什么.
after we run the Yankees
up to Canada.
He said: ''Follow them.
l wanna be the Duke of Montreal.''
他说，跟他们一样.
我要做蒙特利尔公爵."
Oh, that Stonewall.
噢, 那个史东沃.
l once asked him
有一次我问他
觉得我应该
跟林肯干吗.
what he thought
l should do with Lincoln.
And he says, ''Old Honest Abe
is about as useful to you
他就说, "那个老实巴交的亚伯
对你来说，
as a spittoon cleaner
in a whorehouse.''
充其量不过是个
妓院的床底尿壶罢了."
旅行者，稳住了.
Traveler.
你怎么看, 杰柯比医生?
What do you think, Dr. Jacoby?
带他出来逛
看来也没什么帮助.
Letting him out to mingle with the
public doesn't seem to have helped.
嗯, 但你得承认,
他在这倒玩的挺开心的.
Well, you have to admit,
he's kind of fun this way.
你也犯病了?
那可是我爸, 你哥呀.
What's the matter with you?
That's my father, your brother.
We can't leave him like this.
我们不能由他这样.
Well, now, Audrey, honey, now.
好, 现在, 欧蕊, 小甜甜, 听我说.
There are some advantages
to leaving him...insane.
由他这样疯
还是有点好处的.
--told me that every man,
woman and child...
--告诉我所有男人,
女人和小孩的事...
Now, Audrey,
you know l was upset too,
现在, 欧蕊,
你知道我也心烦,
but there's some projects,
both domestic and international,
但现在我或许有机会,
去发展一些,
国内和国际
业务了.
that l'd might get a chance
to develop.
l mean, one man's crisis
is another man's opportunity.
我是说, 一鸡死
一鸡鸣.
我告诉你些事,
杰里叔叔.
Let me tell you something,
Uncle Jerry.
我们由他这样的话,
那我就变成财产遗属执行人了.
We leave him the way he is,
and l become executor of the estate.
Audrey, it's a little more complicated
than that, sweetheart.
欧蕊, 这事可没那么
简单, 甜心.
不, 就这么简单.
我会验收他的遗属, 杰里.
No, it isn't.
l've examined his will, Jerry.
lf my father becomes incapacitated,
it all goes to me when l'm old enough.
如果我父亲不能再胜任了,
等我到了法定年龄，一切都归我所有.
我刚好够年龄了, 杰,
而他也刚好不能再胜任了.
And l am old enough, Jer,
and he is incapacitated.
l have my way either way.
不管怎样，我有自己的做事方式.
When the only project
you'll be developing
当你唯一能发展的
项目就是在
is selling baseboard heaters
at the local Cash 'n' Carry.
当地买现卖期交易所
推销挂壁暖气时 .
What's happened to the man
is a tragedy.
那堪称
一个男人的悲剧.
就是一个悲剧, 杰.
lt is a tragedy, Jer.
Dr. Jacoby,
l want you to bring my father back.
杰柯比医生,
我要你把我爸爸带回来.
- 会办公室吗?
- 列队, 稍息!
- To the office?
- Parade, rest!
To the real world.
回现实世界.
l think it's time we implement
the Appomattox scenario.
我想是时候执行
阿波马托克斯方案了.
嘿, 抱歉我来晚了. 2个机车党
想抢我这外套.
Hey, sorry l'm late. A couple of bikers
tried to take this jacket.
但老史东沃
现在已离我而去,
But old Stonewall's
gone from me now,
cut down in a hail of Yankee lead.
在北佬的一片欢呼声中被杀死了.
他独自死去,
He died alone,
没有我的抚慰.
without my comfort.
拉蒂.
Laddy.
Come here.
过来这儿.
You know what l wanna hear.
Troops, about face.
你知我想听到什么.
部队, 向后转.
"南方州际." "南方州际"!
''Dixie.'' ''Dixie''!
Forward, march.
向前, 起步走.
Oh, l wish l was in the land of cotton
噢, 我愿此刻身在棉花地里
过往美好日子永不忘怀
Old times there were not forgotten
放眼远方, 放眼远方, 放眼远方
南方州际
Look away, look away, look away
Dixie land
Oh, l wish...
噢, 我多希望...
玛舒太太?
Mrs. Marsh?
我是唐娜, 詹姆斯的朋友.
l'm Donna, James' friend.
l remember you.
我认得你.
Get the lady here a drink.
给这位小姐来杯饮料.
要带小伞装饰的.
With a little umbrella in it.
Go on, dear, sit down, it's all right.
继续吧, 亲爱的, 来坐下, 放松点.
- 你为什么要这样对詹姆斯?
- 那为什么不?
- Why are you doing this to James?
- Why not?
Because he's a good person.
因为他是个好人.
He was good at two things:
他对2样东西都好:
The car and me.
车和我.
You don't get it, do you?
l'm talking about our lives.
你还不懂, 是吧?
我现在讲的是我们的生活.
Life. Life will be rosy if you can
just get out of one silly little jam.
生活. 生活是美好的
道路是曲折的.
也许是.
Maybe.
Maybe not.
也许不是.
几年后
Talk to me in a couple of years
等你的生活遭的一坨屎一样
你再来和我讲人生大道理吧.
when your whole life
has turned to crap.
你非得要把每件事搞得毫无意义
或者愚蠢至极，你才安心是吧？
You really like to make everything
sound pointless and stupid.
lf there was a reason to climb out
of this primeval swill,
如果这世上有一个理由
能从这肮脏混世中爬上来,
believe me, dear, l'd know it.
相信我, 亲爱的, 我早就上岸了.
Would you, really?
你会么, 你真的会吗?
Oh, here we are.
The car's waiting, Mrs. Marsh.
哦, 我们该走了.
车子在等着呢, 玛舒太太.
Get in it.
上车去吧.
l'm sorry about your friend, honey.
There's nothing you can do.
我为你朋友的事感到很难过, 小蜜糖.
你帮不上什么的.
So why don't you trundle along
to your little town,
所以，你为什么不自个儿乖乖
滚回你的那个小镇,
要知道那儿安全多了,
如果再让我看到你,
safe in the knowledge that,
if l ever see you here again,
l'll kill you.
我会杀了你.
Don't do this to him, please.
别那样对他, 求你了.
Please.
求你了.
库, 看一下这个.
Coop, take a look at this.
Vicuna thread sample
taken from Josie's coat.
乔西大衣上取的
骆马毛线的样本.
Traces found on the floor
outside your room.
这是你房间外地板上
找到的毛线.
They're from the same coat?
它们来自同一件大衣上?
Let me put it to you this way,
either Josie Packard pulled the trigger,
让我这样跟你说吧,
要不就是乔西·帕卡开的枪,
要不就是她把她的冬衣
错借给坏人穿了.
or she's loaning her winter wear
to the wrong people.
- lt's a perfect match.
- What about the gloves?
- 完全吻合.
- 那手套呢?
Checking for powder burns.
l'll have the results in the morning.
正在检测弹药伤痕.
我早上就会拿到结果.
是西雅图的凶案?
From the Seattle Homicide?
Locals are looking
for a beautiful Asian woman,
当局正在找
一名美丽的亚洲女人,
late 20s, in connection with the murder
of one Jonathan Kumagai.
约二十七、八岁, 乔纳森·曲末该谋杀案
嫌疑人 .
He has an lnterpol sheet
as long as your arm
曲末该先生的跨国犯案表
有你的手臂那么长
and three holes
in the back of his head.
还有3个洞
在他后脑勺.
l'm betting the bullets will match
the slugs we took from your vest.
我敢断定子弹和你背心上
取下来的弹片相符合.
l hope it's not Josie,
for Harry's sake.
我希望不是乔西,
为了哈里.
Coop, as you know, Truman and l
have had our differences in the past.
库, 你也知道, 杜鲁门和我
有着不同的过去.
But the big lug's got his heart
in the right place, if nothing else.
但如无意外的话，他的好心肠
给人利用了.
And l'm not above feeling a little
sympathy for the stalwart and the dull.
我丝毫感觉不到那家伙
对这高大呆有一点怜悯之心.
- What's you point, Albert?
- Speaking frankly?
- 你想说什么, 艾伯特?
- 说实话吗?
Feel free.
说吧.
我们的紧张和她女友
麻烦大了.
Our sheriff's got a serious problem
with his girlfriend.
Albert,
艾伯特,
not one word until we're certain.
我们确证之前一个字也别乱说.
Coop.
库.
Our John Doe's got a name:
我们的约翰·豆找到一个名字:
Erik Powell. Transient.
Former merchant marine by his prints.
埃里·鲍尔. 暂住人员.
这上面说他是前商船的.
Powell?
鲍尔?
Yeah, ring a bell?
是啊, 想起什么了?
Powell was Caroline's
maiden name.
鲍尔是凯若琳
女佣的名字.
Do you think
this Powell is a relative?
你觉得
这个鲍尔是亲戚吗?
No. Earle's playing the game
according to his own rules.
不. 厄尔有他自己
的游戏规则.
Every move he makes
sends a message.
他每个举措
都是在发出信息.
The fact that he chose
the name Powell
事实上，是他故意选了
一个叫鲍尔的人
tells me he hasn't forgotten a thing
that went on between us.
他在告诉我，他一直
没有忘记我们之间的恩怨.
So whenever he takes a piece
from the board...
所以，每当他从棋盘上
走出一步...
Someone dies.
就有人要死.
l never beat him, Harry.
我从没打败过他, 哈里.
Coop, if you've got a need
for a chess expert,
库, 如果你需要一个
下棋高手,
we've got one of the best
right here in town.
我们镇上正
有个最好的.
Checkmate.
将军.
And mate.
再将.
Frankly, l am impressed.
坦白说, 我服了.
l owe it all
to the great Jose Raul Capablanca.
这都得归功于
象棋大师何西·楼·卡柏布兰卡.
Now, if there's chess boards
in heaven,
此刻, 如果天堂
也有棋盘,
Jose's sitting next to the Lord.
何西一定就坐在主的对面.
- Doc?
- The mind reels.
- 医圣?
- 脑袋都转成团了.
One of these days.
总有一天.
Pete, l need your help.
皮特, 我需要你帮助.
l'm playing a chess match
of considerable importance.
我正进行着一场
相当重要的象棋竞赛.
l can't say any more than that.
我无法透露更多.
Suffice to say,
l'd like to stalemate the game,
只能说,
我宁愿僵持着,
losing as few pieces as possible.
None, if that can be arranged.
尽可能减少损失.
或不损失, 如果能重整棋局.
Well, Agent Cooper,
l'd be proud to serve.
那好, 库珀探员,
我很荣幸有用武之地.
Thanks, Pete.
谢谢, 皮特.
Great players are either far or few.
伟大的棋手少之又少啊.
- Hi.
- Shelly.
- 嗨.
- 雪莉.
l'm sorry about what happened.
发生了那些事，我真难过.
Are you okay?
你还好吧?
Not really.
不怎么的.
l wanted to come right over,
我本来过去看你的,
but with Hank gone,
it's been a madhouse here.
但汉克不在之后,
这里简直成了疯人院.
You don't need any help, do you?
你不需要帮手了, 是吧?
l... l'd...
我... 我想...
l'd feel safer, Norma.
我觉得安全多了, 诺玛.
Are you kidding?
你不是开玩笑吧?
lt hasn't been the same without you.
这儿没有你，完全不同.
When can you start?
你几时能开始?
- Now?
- Great. Welcome back.
- 现在啊?
- 太好了. 欢迎回来.
Thank you.
谢谢你.
Norma?
诺玛?
- Hi, Shelly.
- Hi.
- 嗨, 雪莉.
- 嗨.
Excuse me.
l need to talk to you for a minute.
打搅了.
我要和你谈几分钟.
There's something you should know.
有些事你应该要知道.
Hank's nearly ready
to leave the hospital.
汉克快准备
出院了.
What about his parole violations?
他不是触犯假释条例了吗?
Harry, this time
l don't want him back.
哈里, 这次
我不想他回来了.
Don't worry. He won't be back.
Hank's going to jail.
别担心. 他不会回来了.
汉克要蹲大牢了.
We're charging him with
the attempted murder of Leo Johnson.
我们正准备起诉他
企图谋杀里欧·强生.
Add that to breaking parole,
加上违反假释条例,
Hank's going away for a long time.
汉克会离开好长一段时间了.
Good.
好.
Mr. Eckhardt, welcome.
埃卡先生, 欢迎光临.
Josie, help our guest with his coat.
乔西, 帮客人脱大衣啊.
l must confess l received
your invitation with some surprise.
我必须得承认
接到你的邀请有点吃惊.
Well, word travels fast
in Twin Peaks.
嗯, 消息在双峰镇
传的可快了.
l thought it was fitting that l dined
with my late brother's business rival.
我想请我已故兄长的生意对手
共进晚餐，是合礼节的.
Some wine, Josie.
来点酒, 乔西.
Your brother was not always my rival.
We were friends.
你哥哥生前也不单是我的竞争对手.
我们也曾经是朋友.
- But your friendship soured.
- Sadly.
- 但你们的友谊变质了.
- 可悲啊.
Men of business frequently find
their personal lives disrupted
生意人常常会发现
他们的私生活被自己
by the larger portraits they paint.
所画的那幅巨大肖像扰乱了.
You consider yourself an artist?
The wine, Josie.
你把自己看作一个艺术家?
酒, 乔西.
Of a sort. Your brother was as well.
算是吧. 你哥哥也算是.
l wonder, Mr. Eckhardt.
我想知道, 埃卡先生.
When you had him killed,
was it for art or money?
但你设计杀他时,
到底是为了艺术还是钱呢?
- Don't stand there, Josie, pour.
- Call me Thomas. Your brother did.
- 别光站着, 乔西, 倒酒.
- 叫我托马斯吧. 你哥哥就这样叫的.
Thomas. We'll have
our hors d'oeuvres now, Josie.
托马斯. 现在上
开胃小菜吧，乔西.
One does not kill for art or money.
一个人不为艺术或钱而杀人.
They are commodities easily lost
and just as easily gained.
这些东西来得容易去得快
无非是些过眼云烟罢了.
However, one, rather l,
might find reason to kill for love.
然而, 一个人, 就说我吧,
却有可能为爱而杀.
- Did you love her that much?
- Yes.
- 你那么爱她吗?
- 是的.
Josie has the most
incredible hands.
乔西有一双
不可思议的美手.
Every finger a thing of beauty.
每一根手指都赏心悦目.
l remember.
我记得.
l wonder,
what shall we do about her?
我在想,
我们要怎么处理她呢?
lt would be a shame
if you left empty-handed.
如果让你空手而回
那多不好意思啊.
Of course,
l'll miss her cheery disposition.
当然,我会想念她那
让人快乐的性情.
We've become the best of friends.
我们曾经做过好朋友.
Two girls chatting over tea.
两个女孩喝茶聊天.
Perhaps you should purchase
an animal of some kind.
或许你该买只
动物，或一只其它什么.
A cat or a dog.
猫啊狗啊之类.
lf l give her to you,
what will you give me in return?
如果我把她给你了,
你将会用什么回报我呢?
How can l place a value
on something so precious?
如此珍贵的东西
我又怎么能用价值去衡量呢?
But you will try?
但你会尝试?
Yes.
是的.
Josie.
乔西.
Thomas and l
will have our main course now.
托马斯和我
现在准备要吃主菜了.
Why did you do it?
你为什么要这样做?
You know l've been going through it.
你知道我深受其害的.
- l can't figure it out.
- James, you're not safe here.
- 我解决不了.
- 詹姆斯, 你在这不安全.
- lf Malcolm finds you--
- ls it the money?
- 如果马科发现你--
- 为了钱吗?
ls that it? No. No, l got it.
是那样吗? 不. 不, 我明白了.
lt was Malcolm. Oh, yeah.
He made you do it. Right?
是马科. 哦, 对了.
是他让你这样干的. 对吧?
You better tell me a story, Evelyn.
Because l'm all mixed up.
你最好把故事给我编好点, 伊夫林.
因为我全糊涂了.
l just wanna know
why you would do this to me.
我只想知道
你为什么要这样对我.
James.
詹姆斯.
What did you expect? An apology?
A hidden heart of gold?
你能期待什么呢? 一个道歉?
一颗金子般的心?
l did it all, James. l did everything.
都是我做的, 詹姆斯. 所有事都是我做的.
l found you, l lured you in
and l kept you here,
当时，马科正设计着
一个完美无缺的小陷阱.
while Malcolm planned
a nice, neat little frame.
是我发现了你, 引诱你进来
还把你留在了这儿,
- Why?
- For the money.
- 为什么?
- 为了钱.
Out of fear.
出于恐惧.
Because l wanted to do it.
因此我想这样做.
lt's not exactly what you wanted
to hear, is it, James?
这可不是你想要听到的
是吧, 詹姆斯?
The truth hurts, doesn't it?
真相很伤人吧, 不是吗?
James, you're good
and you're honest.
詹姆斯, 你是个
诚实的好人.
l'm not.
我不是.
But that doesn't mean
there weren't moments
但不代表
我想你留下来那一刻
when l truly wanted you here.
不是真的.
Not for Malcolm,
不为马科,
or for the money, but for me.
也不为钱, 只为我.
For the good and honest way
that you taste.
为了尝到你的好
你的诚实.
l like how you taste too.
我也喜欢你品尝.
Malcolm, what did you do?
James, James. You hurt him.
马科, 你干什么?
詹姆斯, 詹姆斯. 你打伤他了.
He broke into the house,
他破门而入,
he was angry, he was crazy.
他发怒, 他抓狂.
He killed Jeffrey
and he came back to kill you.
他杀了杰弗里
现在又回来杀你.
You poor, defenseless little widow.
你是可怜的, 毫无防备的小寡妇.
But you were ready for him, Evelyn.
但你早知他会回来的, 伊夫林.
You got your gun,
所以你准备了你的手枪,
and you shot James.
你开枪打了詹姆斯.
You shot him until he was dead.
你一直开枪直到打死了他.
- General Lee.
- Whoa.
- 李将军.
- 喔.
Welcome to our humble horse--
Home, General Lee.
欢迎光临寒马--
寒舍, 李将军.
- Thank you. And you are...?
- Scarlett McLean.
- 谢谢你. 你是...?
- 史佳丽·麦琳.
And this is my father--
这是我爸爸--
This is my father.
这是我爸爸.
Wilmer McLean at your service.
威尔默·麦琳随时听候你的差遣.
l'm indeed honored to be making
your extremely sociable acquaintance.
我真的非常荣幸能
如此亲近友好的与你结交.
And why are you armed
with my sword, sir?
你拿着我的剑
干什么, 先生?
l like your sword, sire.
我喜欢你的剑, 陛下.
- Thank you, Daddy. Thank you.
- Where is General Grant?
- 谢谢你, 爸爸. 谢谢你.
- 格兰将军呢?
General Grant's a-coming, sire,
l know it.
格兰将军正来呢, 陛下,
我知道的.
Excuse us.
失陪了.
General Grant.
格兰将军.
General Lee.
李将军.
Sir, we met during the Mexican War.
Do you remember?
先生, 我们是在墨西哥战争中相遇的.
你还记得吧?
l have come to surrender the North.
我是来投降，并交出北方的.
The Mexican War, sir.
Do you remember?
墨西哥战争, 先生.
你还记得吗?
Oh, yes, yes.
lt was a good war, as l remember.
哦, 记得, 记得.
我记得那是场漂亮仗.
Nonsense.
All wars are nothing but madness.
胡说八道.
所有战争除了愚蠢疯狂之外，一无是处.
Disguised as the patriotic ventures
of politicians,
不过是政客们打着爱国主义旗号
去投机倒把的假面而已,
too old and too cowardly
to participate in them.
太老太懦弱
以至于他们不能参与其中.
- No, no, sir, l have no love for war.
- Me neither.
- 不, 不, 先生, 我对战争没有任何感情.
- 我也没有.
- And even less for politicians.
- Hey, amen.
- 甚至比政客们还少.
- 嘿, 阿门.
But, as for the men who fight them,
但, 对于英勇作战的战士们,
they have my eternal respect
and sympathy.
他们值得我永垂不朽的尊敬
和哀悼.
All right, general,
enough of this fruitless conversation.
好了, 将军,
这没完没了的对话够了.
My terms:
用我的话说:
Federal officers
may keep their sidearms
联邦官员们
可以保留他们的武器
and other general possessions.
和其他将军的财产.
Officers and men claiming to own
their own horses may keep them too.
军官们和士兵们可以去
认领自己的马，并留着它们自用.
And officers and men will be allowed
to return to their home,
军官们和士兵们
可以回自己老家了,
not to be disturbed
by the Confederate States' authorities.
再也不会被邦联当局
骚扰了.
- l surrender.
- Of course you do.
- 我投降了.
- 你当然了.
The articles.
条约.
- Here, sire, the articles.
- Sir.
- 在这儿, 陛下, 条约.
- 先生.
The articles, sir.
条约, 先生.
- You will sign, General Grant.
-Oh, yes, yes, yes.
- 你会签吧, 格兰将军.
-哦, 会签, 会签, 当然了.
And may l add that, that you've been
a valiant opponent of fine character.
可以让我加上这个, 你一直是个
英勇抗战的出色人物.
l thought the North won
the Civil War?
我觉得是北方
赢了内战吧，不是吗?
Ben?
本?
Ben.
本.
Daddy.
爸爸.
- Ben? Ben?
- Daddy?
- 本? 本?
-爸爸?
Hey, give him some room.
嘿, 给他点空间.
Where am l?
我在哪儿?
- Where am l?
- Twin Peaks, Ben.
- 我在哪儿?
- 双峰镇, 本.
l had the strangest dream.
我做了个奇怪的梦.
And you were there.
你在梦里.
And you, and you.
你也在, 还有你.
lt was incredible.
太不可思议了.
lt was a war.
那是一场战争.
And l was General...
我是将军...
General Robert E. Lee.
罗伯特·伊·李将军.
And somehow,
in spite of incredible odds,
然而不知怎的,
尽管在微乎其微的几率下,
l won.
我赢了.
Now you're home, Daddy.
你现在回家了, 爸爸.
Yes.
是的.
- l'm home.
- Attaboy, Ben.
- 我回家了.
- 好样的啊, 本.
How do you feel?
Any, any aftereffects? Dizziness?
你感觉怎样?
有任何, 余波? 头昏眼花之类?
l feel terrific.
我感觉好极了.
- l feel...
- Yes?
- 我感觉...
- 怎样?
- What is it, Daddy?
- What are you doing in those clothes?
- 感觉什么, 爸爸?
- 你们穿这这些衣服干嘛?
Attaboy, Ben.
好样的, 本.
What? What's the joke?
什么? 有什么那么好笑的?
Attaboy, Ben.
好样的, 本.
Work slowly.
慢慢做.
And with care.
而且要细致.
Everything must be written
with a steady, uncompromising hand.
每个字都要写的
沉稳，坚定不移的.
No, no, no.
不, 不, 不.
Terrible.
太吓人了.
Erase.
擦掉.
Now...
现在...
Try again.
再来一次.
Concentrate.
集中精神.
Leo, for heaven's sake.
里欧, 看在老天爷的份上.
Here.
这儿.
Let me show you.
我示范给你看.
Like this:
像这样:
There you go.
你看.
Much better.
好多了吧.
l am proud of you, Leo.
我真为你自豪, 里欧.
- Windom Earle?
- Yes.
- 云顿·厄尔?
- 是.
Windom.
云顿.
Pretty words for pretty girls.
好字配美女.
Which one shall be my queen?
哪一个会是我的皇后呢?
Queen?
皇后?
No. No.
不. 不.
No.
不.
Lick.
舔.
The story rings a little truer
with your fingerprints on--
有你的指纹在上面的话
这个故事就显得更真实了--
No, Malcolm, l can't.
不, 马科, 我不能.
Just your prints.
Leave the rest to me.
只要你的指纹.
其余的事交给我来办好了.
l'll do my best to imitate
the actions of a hysteric.
我会尽量去模仿现场
歇斯底里的举动.
Five shots, tightly grouped,
5枪, 紧紧集中在一处,
as though the gun went off
in your hand.
就像从你这儿
打出去的一样.
- Repeatedly.
- No!
- 连开多枪.
- 别!
No! No! James, James, James.
别! 别! 詹姆斯, 詹姆斯, 詹姆斯.
- Don't hurt him any more, please.
- Give me the gun.
- 不要再伤害他了, 求你们了.
- 给我枪.
l've called the cops.
They're on their way, it won't work.
我已经报警了.
他们已经在路上了, 你们不会得逞的.
- Malcolm.
- She's lying. Give me the gun.
- 马科.
- 她在撒谎. 给我枪.
Evelyn,
please don't let him die, please.
伊夫林,
求你别让他死啊, 求你了.
- Please.
- Evelyn.
- 求求你.
- 伊夫林.
Give me the gun, Evelyn.
把枪给我, 伊夫林.
- Evelyn, give me the gun.
- No.
- 伊夫林, 快把枪给我.
- 不.
- Evelyn, give me the gun.
- No.
- 伊夫林, 把枪给我.
- 不.
Evelyn. Evelyn.
伊夫林. 伊夫林.
l can't do this, Malcolm.
我干不出这种事, 马科.
Then l will.
那我干.
No.
不.
He was angry,
他很生气,
he was crazy.
他抓狂了.
He killed Jeffrey,
came back to kill me.
他杀了杰弗里,
又回来杀我.
l was ready, though.
我早有准备, 尽管如此.
l got my gun and l shot him.
我还是开枪打了他.
l shot him till he was dead.
我开枪直到把他打死.
Caroline.
凯若琳.
For Miss Audrey Horne, please.
请转交欧蕊·荷恩小姐.
Owls?
猫头鹰?
Breathtaking, wasn't she?
她很惊艷, 不是吗?
A truly beautiful woman, Caroline.
一个真正的美人, 凯若琳.
Funny, isn't it?
有趣吧?
After all this time,
经过匹兹堡那次,
after all that happened
in Pittsburgh,
发生了那么多事
之后,
l still love her.
我依然爱着她.
And l know that you do too.
我知道你也是.
Now, Dale, listen carefully.
现在, 戴尔, 小心听好了.
lt's your move.
轮到你走了.